<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 09:53:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customer Support Chatbot for the Chemistry Industry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/chemistry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I led the development of an intelligent chatbot solution tailored for customer support and product recommendations in the chemistry industry. The chatbot leveraged state-of-the-art Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to process vast amounts of product information sourced from the company&amp;rsquo;s website and internal documents. Within just three months, I successfully delivered a fully functional, end-to-end solution that smoothly integrated with the company’s workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By employing advanced techniques such as prompt engineering, text summarization and a two-layer search system, I significantly improved the chatbot&amp;rsquo;s ability to deliver precise and contextually relevant responses. The innovative search mechanism combined product name filtering with relation matching, enabling the chatbot to handle complex multi-hop questions effectively. To ensure transparency and user trust, I incorporated Responsible AI mechanisms, providing clear justifications for product recommendations and aligning the solution with the company’s ethical standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart AI Chatbot with Image Understanding &amp; Enterprise Integration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/chatbot_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/chatbot_images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced business environments, communication workflows often rely on multiple data formats, including text and images. To address this challenge, I enriched a chatbot solution with an image ingestion pipeline that allowed the chatbot to analyze and integrate visual data into its knowledge base. This breakthrough enabled users to ask questions not only about textual content but also about images, making multimodal question answering a reality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the chatbot&amp;rsquo;s ability to process and retrieve visual data, I also developed Outlook and Microsoft Teams connectors, enabling flawless integration with enterprise communication workflows and making the chatbot more customizable and accessible to users by allowing them to interact with it directly within familiar tools. This integration streamlined workflows, reduced friction in information retrieval, and enabled organizations to tailor the chatbot’s responses and capabilities to their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable AI for Fraud Prevention in Banking: From 10 Million to 9 Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/fraud_prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/fraud_prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fraud detection in banking is a high-stakes challenge, where every false positive disrupts legitimate customers, and every false negative costs millions. My mission was to enhance fraud prevention while simplifying complexity—turning an unmanageable 10 million model setup into a highly efficient 9-model solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough came from an optimized customer segmentation strategy, which allowed us to dramatically reduce the number of required models without compromising predictive accuracy. This streamlined model training, deployment and evaluation, making fraud prevention scalable and cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered KYC Automation &amp; Fraud Prevention in Financial Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the world of financial services, ensuring compliance while providing a seamless user experience is a delicate balance. The Know Your Customer (KYC) process, a critical requirement for bank account openings, often suffers from manual inefficiencies and fraud risks. My goal was to automate and optimize KYC verification, leveraging the power of deep learning and computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I led the development of an AI-driven KYC solution, which streamlined identity verification, ensuring that customers could onboard faster, safer and with minimal friction. A major milestone was improving the recognition accuracy of German ID security features by 60%, thanks to advanced deep learning models and computer vision techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Robotics: Smarter Motion Planning with Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/rl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern robotics, efficiency and adaptability are key to automating complex tasks, especially in manufacturing and logistics. My mission was to develop intelligent robotic systems that could perceive, learn and act autonomously, leveraging reinforcement learning, synthetic data and real-time inference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To train AI models for robotic object picking, I designed and generated synthetic training data, creating artificial 3D environments that simulated real-world tasks. This approach eliminated the need for expensive real-world data collection, making the system scalable and highly adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
