<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:50:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dana Oneal</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/testimonial/dana-oneal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:50:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/testimonial/dana-oneal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add LinkedIn recommendations here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Responsible Generative AI Products: From Concepts to Implementation</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/webinar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 AI &#43; 2 GenAI Use Cases That Bring Early Value</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/whitepaper/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customer Support Chatbot for the Chemistry Industry</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/chemistry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I led the development of an intelligent chatbot solution tailored for customer support and product recommendations in the chemistry industry. The chatbot leveraged state-of-the-art Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to process vast amounts of product information sourced from the company&amp;rsquo;s website and internal documents. Within just three months, I successfully delivered a fully functional, end-to-end solution that smoothly integrated with the company’s workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By employing advanced techniques such as prompt engineering, text summarization and a two-layer search system, I significantly improved the chatbot&amp;rsquo;s ability to deliver precise and contextually relevant responses. The innovative search mechanism combined product name filtering with relation matching, enabling the chatbot to handle complex multi-hop questions effectively. To ensure transparency and user trust, I incorporated Responsible AI mechanisms, providing clear justifications for product recommendations and aligning the solution with the company’s ethical standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart AI Chatbot with Image Understanding &amp; Enterprise Integration</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/chatbot_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/chatbot_images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced business environments, communication workflows often rely on multiple data formats, including text and images. To address this challenge, I enriched a chatbot solution with an image ingestion pipeline that allowed the chatbot to analyze and integrate visual data into its knowledge base. This breakthrough enabled users to ask questions not only about textual content but also about images, making multimodal question answering a reality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the chatbot&amp;rsquo;s ability to process and retrieve visual data, I also developed Outlook and Microsoft Teams connectors, enabling flawless integration with enterprise communication workflows and making the chatbot more customizable and accessible to users by allowing them to interact with it directly within familiar tools. This integration streamlined workflows, reduced friction in information retrieval, and enabled organizations to tailor the chatbot’s responses and capabilities to their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable AI for Fraud Prevention in Banking: From 10 Million to 9 Models</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/fraud_prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/fraud_prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fraud detection in banking is a high-stakes challenge, where every false positive disrupts legitimate customers, and every false negative costs millions. My mission was to enhance fraud prevention while simplifying complexity—turning an unmanageable 10 million model setup into a highly efficient 9-model solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough came from an optimized customer segmentation strategy, which allowed us to dramatically reduce the number of required models without compromising predictive accuracy. This streamlined model training, deployment and evaluation, making fraud prevention scalable and cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered KYC Automation &amp; Fraud Prevention in Financial Services</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the world of financial services, ensuring compliance while providing a seamless user experience is a delicate balance. The Know Your Customer (KYC) process, a critical requirement for bank account openings, often suffers from manual inefficiencies and fraud risks. My goal was to automate and optimize KYC verification, leveraging the power of deep learning and computer vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I led the development of an AI-driven KYC solution, which streamlined identity verification, ensuring that customers could onboard faster, safer and with minimal friction. A major milestone was improving the recognition accuracy of German ID security features by 60%, thanks to advanced deep learning models and computer vision techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Developer</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-driven-solutions-enhancing-finance-chemistry--customer-support&#34;&gt;AI-Driven Solutions: Enhancing Finance, Chemistry &amp;amp; Customer Support&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented AI-powered solutions across multiple industries, including financial services, chemistry and customer support, driving innovation and operational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Led end-to-end chatbot development for customer support, implementing retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines, prompt engineering and Responsible AI mechanisms to ensure transparency and high-quality recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimized fraud prevention strategies by simplifying model pipelines, reducing the number of required models through effective customer segmentation and improving performance with enhanced feature engineering.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python · Microsoft Azure · Java · Docker · OpenSearch · TensorFlow · XGBoost · Spring Boot · PySpark  · MLflow · Pandas · NumPy · Scikit-Network · Pyplot · JUnit · Pytest · FitNesse · HDFS · Apache HBase · Apache Kafka&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How users attend to online comments: an eye-tracking approach</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/publications/thesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Developer</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyc-automation--fraud-prevention-in-financial-services&#34;&gt;KYC Automation &amp;amp; Fraud Prevention in Financial Services&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Led the development and optimization of the AI component for a KYC (Know Your Customer) process, ensuring seamless integration into the application for bank account openings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improved the recognition accuracy of German ID security features by 60% on average through deep learning and computer vision techniques.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Solved complex business problems and implemented fraud prevention algorithms using deep learning and computer vision algorithms, delivering tailored solutions for financial service needs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python · TensorFlow · OpenCV · Pytesseract · Pandas · NumPy · Scikit-Learn · Pytest&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Robotics: Smarter Motion Planning with Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/projects/rl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern robotics, efficiency and adaptability are key to automating complex tasks, especially in manufacturing and logistics. My mission was to develop intelligent robotic systems that could perceive, learn and act autonomously, leveraging reinforcement learning, synthetic data and real-time inference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To train AI models for robotic object picking, I designed and generated synthetic training data, creating artificial 3D environments that simulated real-world tasks. This approach eliminated the need for expensive real-world data collection, making the system scalable and highly adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision Developer</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-driven-automation--robotics&#34;&gt;AI-Driven Automation &amp;amp; Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed synthetic training data for machine learning models using Blender, creating artificial 3D environments to simulate object-picking tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Applied reinforcement learning techniques to optimize robotic motion planning, improving efficiency and adaptability in dynamic environments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developed an object detection solution in Python that performed real-time inference on the Movidius Stick, enabling efficient image capture and decision-making processes in manufacturing environments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python · TensorFlow · OpenCV · NumPy · Pytesseract · Pandas · Scikit-Learn · Pytest · Blender&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices-optimization--automated-testing-in-banking-systems&#34;&gt;Microservices Optimization &amp;amp; Automated Testing in Banking Systems&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimized and extended microservice architecture in a large-scale banking system, ensuring seamless integration with Apache Kafka for real-time event processing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implemented robust algorithms and data structures to enhance backend processing speed and ensure reliable data handling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developed and executed unit and integration tests using Apache JMeter, ensuring the correctness and reliability of core banking system functionalities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Java · Apache Kafka · Apache JMeter&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Scientist</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;crypto-market-insights--alert-systems&#34;&gt;Crypto Market Insights &amp;amp; Alert Systems&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Analyzed cryptocurrency market trends and emerging blockchain projects, assessing investment potential.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developed a Telegram-based automated alert system to notify users when account balances fell below predefined thresholds, ensuring uninterrupted trading operations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Applied analytical skills and data-driven insights to assist decision-making in a fast-paced startup environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TypeScript&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency Market Analysis · Blockchain Technology · Analytical Skills · Telegram Bot Development · Real-Time Alert Systems&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision Engineer</title>
      <link>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://luosua.github.io/portfolio/experience/job-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-powered-robotic-pick-and-place-automation&#34;&gt;AI-Powered Robotic Pick-and-Place Automation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developed AI-driven object recognition algorithms to automate pick-and-place operations for conveyor belt systems, improving efficiency in industrial automation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and optimized real-time distance calculation methods to accurately determine object positions from camera images, ensuring precise robotic movements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implemented a custom HALCON extension for high-speed image capture and storage, enabling seamless integration with machine vision pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;key-technologies--skills&#34;&gt;Key Technologies &amp;amp; Skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C++ · OpenCV · HALCON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision · Image Processing · AI-Driven Pick-and-Place · Industrial Automation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
